Guide to the Office of Trusts and Estates, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Office of Trusts and Estates, Yale University, records
1940-2017
RU 960
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
251.17
(242 boxes)
The records consist of completed files of individual trusts and estates maintained by the Yale Office of Trusts and Estates.
Yale University. Office of Finance and Administration
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 5-B (YRG 5-B), Accounting records and records of the Yale comptroller.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records were transferred from the Yale Office of Trusts and Estates, 2004-2018.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the materials is partially restricted. See inventory for details.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of completed files of individual trusts and estates maintained by the Yale Office of Trusts and Estates.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Endowments; Gifts; Universities and colleges -- Finance; Yale University -- Benefactors; Yale University -- Endowments; Yale University -- Finance; Yale University. Office of Finance and Administration
- Completed files on individuals' trusts and estates, circa 1940-2004; Accession 2004-A-185
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2040
  - Anlyan, A. John (5% CRUT) (Box 1, Folder 13 - 15)
  - Blaser, Arthur F. (9% CRUT) (Box 2, Folder 52 - 53)
  - Brown, Daniel N. '28 (7% CRAT) (Box 2, Folder 72 - 73)
  - Crisler, Richard C. '29 (6% CRUT) (Box 4, Folder 136 - 138)
  - Hall, Joseph Twichell (8% CRUT) (Box 7, Folder 249)
  - Hixon, Alexander P. '38 (5% CRUT) (Box 8, Folder 295 - 296)
  - Ten Eick, Majorie J. (6% CRUT) (Box 15, Folder 544 - 546)
- Records of completed files on individuals' trusts and estates, 2004; Accession 2005-A-035
- Records of files closed pre 2003-2005, Accession 2007-A-007
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2041
- Pooled income fund statements and accounting transfers, 2002-2004; Accession 2007-A-009
- Charitable gift annuity statements, 2002-2004; Accession 2007-A-010
- Trust, estate, and gift records, 2007; Accession 2008-A-046
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2043
  Separated Materials
  Box 28 Folder 351: Jayne, Harold P. & Melgaard, Edna Trusts, has been returned to the Office of Trusts and Estates permanently.
  Box 26 Folder 287: Douglas, Richard Alexander Estate, has been returned to the Office of Trusts and Estates permanently.
  Box 41 Folder 511: Melon, Paul Estate, has been returned to the Office of Trusts and Estates permanently.
  - Branin, M. Lelyn Grad "27; 7% CRUT (Box 24, Folder 224 - 225)
  - Brightwell, Henry P. Jr. "35; 8% CRUT (Box 24, Folder 228 - 229)
- Trusts and Estates records, 2007; Accession 2009-A-047
- Ken Dayton, Oak Leaf Endowment trust files, 1996-2005; Accession 2009-A-062
- Gift, Bequest, and Life Income records, circa 1971-2010; Accession 2013-A-025
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2045
- Card catalog of treasurer files and other financial records, 1900-2000; Accession 2008-A-047
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2036
- Gift, Bequest, and Life Income records, 1959-2015; Accession 2017-A-012
  Restricted until January 1, 2091
- Trusts and Estates records, 1975-2015; Accession 2017-A-021
- Special assets and donor files, Accession 2018-A-028
  Office of Origin only
- Trusts and Estates records, FY 2017; Accession 2019-A-0014
  Restricted until January 1, 2093